Contact

chuckwilliams37@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ chuckcwilliams (LinkedIn) tlc.howstuffworks.com/tv/sayyes-to-the-dress/virtual-bridalboutique.htm (Other) www.teamtrek.com (Other) www.qwest.com/business/ (Other)

Top Skills

Flash jQuery ActionScript

Languages

jQuery (Native or Bilingual)
ColdFusion (CFML) (Full
Professional)
Actionscript (Full Professional)

Certifications

Agile: SCRUM - Rally

Patents

Methods and systems for designing photo books

Chuck Williams

Tech Lead at Equa Start; Radio Cohost at The Crypto Show; Dash: Crypto Activist; Patented Developer; Public Speaker Kailua, Hawaii

Summary

Listed as inventor of 2 patents (Shutterfly's Photobook Application, and Level3's Dynamic Prompt System). History with visual design and User Experience (UX) oriented strategies and implementations. Current favorite technologies now include React/Redux/Firebase, AngularJS, NodeJS, MongoDB and the related ecosystem of build and dependency management tools (Webpack, Jest, Gulp, Grunt, Bower, etc.).

Contributed to projects affecting the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI which oversees the FBI & CIA). Facilitated meetings with high-profile media executives at National Geographic, Discovery, and The Learning Channels, Qwest and Level 3 Communications. Authored code for FedEx's Print Online Application allowing customers to upload and retrieve documents from FedEx Office Locations.

Strengths include excellent business communications skills, measurable productivity, strategic planning, project direction, team management, and elegant problem solving in the realms of application code, systems architecture, and data management.

Twenty-consecutive-year history with ECMAScript (JavaScript & ActionScript), HTML, & CSS. Also competent with React, AngularJS, NodeJS, PHP, ColdFusion, MySQL, MSSQL, OracleSQL, Grunt, Adobe Fireworks, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, 3D Studio MAX, Ableton Live, and Audio Mixing Board technology. Familiar with design patterns, client relations & presentations, and digital innovation and transformation strategies.

Experience

EQUA Start
Product, Experience, and Technical Development Lead
Page 1 of 5

December 2018 - Present

Global

Evaluating, researching, developing, strategizing, and evangelizing business simplification.

The Crypto Show Radio Cohost June 2018 - Present United States

Little Blue Dot

Self-employed Human Endeavor Contributor / Crypto Systems Advisor June 2018 - Present

Dash - Digital Cash (Cryptocurrency)
UX / UI Technical Lead
January 2017 - June 2018 (1 year 6 months)
Scottsdale, AZ

https://www.dash.org

Screen Scholar Owner / Programmer May 2007 - June 2018 (11 years 2 months)

Freelance opportunities are evaluated and committed on a project-by-project basis under this name. Projects are accepted only if commitments can be satisfactorily fulfilled.

PlayerLync User Experience & Interface Lead January 2015 - May 2017 (2 years 5 months) Centennial, CO

I'm helping to construct a beautiful and useful experience for data-intensive content. Enterprise administrators, distributors, and consumers, web, and mobile product users are at the heart of PlayerLync's business communications for organizations with mobile-device focused distributed teams.

Clients include Chipotle, The Denver Broncos (and many other football teams), Old Chicago's, Lexus, Spavia, David's Bridal, and many others.

OppenheimerFunds
Senior Programmer Analyst Internet
September 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 4 months)
Parker, CO

AngularJS, SASS, Ruby on Rails (Limited), UI / UX

Level 3 Communications
Software Architect
September 2011 - September 2013 (2 years 1 month)

Filed patent as inventor for a dynamic data-driven prompt interface with Level 3. Focused on production implementations of customer portal systems (mylevel3.net), interface design & development using Angular JS, Java Spring, Java, Node JS, jQuery, & BackBone.

EffectiveUI
Senior Software Architect
May 2008 - April 2011 (3 years)

Teamed up with A+ team of Project Managers, Designers, and various other specific roles on a variety of projects for well-known fortune 500 organizations was an absolute dream come true. The deadlines were tight, the hours long, and the meetings tense - but the results of working with an EFFECTIVE team is RESULTS.

Client Communications, Feasibility Analysis, Architecture Analysis, Development Team Lead, Estimations.

NYK Logistics
Development Project Lead
June 2006 - May 2008 (2 years)

With a team of 15 other developers, developed and maintained over 1/2 million lines of Flex, ColdFusion, SQL code. Expert Flex developer on staff, planning, developing, and conducting training sessions assist with team knowledge distribution. Internal and external clients ranging from Accounting to Wal-Mart. Applications produced manage shipments constituting 11 Billion dollars in annual revenue for the Americas division of this Tokyo based international corporation.

NYK Logistics Systems Development Engineer June 2006 - May 2007 (1 year)

- * Developed Double-Wing-Express (DWE) to enable customer visibility for international large-vessel shipment tracking.
- * Designed workflow plan for project tracking and issue management.
- * Analyzed Development Frameworks & Methodologies for departmental review & implementation.

Mind Over Data, LLC

Senior Business Analyst

March 2004 - May 2006 (2 years 3 months)

- * Consulted with clients to produce highly scalable internet business solutions
- * Led a team of up to 5 developers in executing and implementing planned solutions.
- * Estimated project development costs.
- * Interviewed & trained new hires.
- * Clients include: TeamTrek, FedEx, ServiceMaster, TruGreen

The Data Company

Multimedia Development Specialist

April 2002 - March 2004 (2 years)

My main role here was developing courtroom demonstratives in 2D, & 3D for the support of the legal case in courtroom disputes.

Tasks included

- * 3D Animation
- * 2D Animation
- * Storyboard & Graphics development
- * Led a team of up to 3 Graphic designers as Graphics Department Manager
- * Notable Cases included:
- ** Ford v. Firestone (3D Animations)
- ** Scott v. Phillip Morris (2D Animations and Courtroom Graphics)
- ** Adobe v. Macromedia (Courtroom Demonstratives, Adobe)
- ** ElcomSoft v US Dept. of Justice (Graphics & Presentations)

Prisma International

Production Designer

1999 - 2002 (3 years)

Tasks included:

- * Layout multilingual multi-page books & documents for production printing.
- * Execution of planned animations & designs
- * Client relationship interaction.

* Flash & Actionscript Programming & Integration for clients such as Kodak, Panasonic, & 3M.

IKON

Senior Business Collector 1997 - 1999 (2 years)

During my tenure here I conceived, developed and presented a Multimedia sales tool to educate customers on how to work most effectively with IKON staff.

Additionally I developed a system of collection that enabled me to collect 2-3 times as many accounts as my colleagues...which contributed to being awarded IKON's divisional "Most Productive Department" Award.

Education

Academy of Communication Arts
Associate of Arts and Sciences (AAS), Multimedia Design &
Development · (1995 - 1997)

St. Cloud State University - Herberger Business School (1994 - 1995)